二零二五年广东省初中学业水平考试
英语试卷听力部分。
首先播放两分钟的音乐信号，
请监考老师调试好播音设备的音量。
音乐结束后，听力考。
是正式开始。
嗯。
试听到此结束。
一，听说应用。
听句子，请根据所听内容。
选择符合提议的图画，回答问题，
并在答题卡上将对应选项涂黑。
每个句子听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五秒钟的答题时间。
听对话，请根据每段对话的内容回答问题。
从每小题所给的三个选项中选出一个最佳答。
案，并在答题卡上将对应选项涂黑。
每段对话听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五秒钟的答题时间。
听第一段对话，回答第六小题。
Hi Jenny, how is your geography project going?
Not very well, but I've learned a lot from it, so I feel very happy.
Not very well, but I've learned a from it, so I feel very happy.
听第二段对话，回答第七小题。
This blue car looks nice.
Let's take it, shall we?
Well, I like the black one better.
It looks as nice, but costs less.
This blue car looks nice.
Let's take it, shall we?
Well, I like the black one better.
looks as nice, but costs less.
听第三段对话，回答第八小题。
John, do you go fishing every day?
No, only on Saturday mornings.
听第四段对话，回答第九小题。
It's raining so heavily.
We must stop working and stay in a safe place.
You are right.
Safety first. It's raining so heavily.
We must stop working and stay in a safe place.
You are right.
Safety first. Did you watch the live news yesterday,
听第五段对话，回答第十小题。
Do you mean the astronauts going into space?
Yes, it was exciting.
Did you watch the live news yesterday, Jane?
Do you mean the astronauts going into space?
Yes, it was exciting.
听第六段对话，回答第十一至十二小题。
Danny, where are you now?
We are supposed to meet at 7 o
Sorry, I'm still in the taxi.
The traffic was heavy just now.
Take your time.
Find me at table 12 when you get here.
Okay, you can order the food first.
Danny, where are you now?
We are supposed to meet at 7 o
Sorry, I'm still in the taxi.
The traffic was heavy just now.
Take your time.
Find me at table 12 when you get here.
Okay, you can order the food first.
听第七段对话，回答第十三至十五小题。
Kate, how was your Chinese culture class today?
Fantastic! We learn
孙子.
Oh, you mean the great thinker in nation China?
Yes. Our teacher also told us about his book, The Art of War.
I've read that book.
I have a copy.
I'm quite curious.
Can I borrow it?
Sure. Kate, how was your Chinese culture class today?
Fantastic! We learn
孙子.
Oh, you mean the great thinker in nation China?
Yes. Our teacher also told us about his book, The Art of War.
I've read that book.
I have a copy.
I'm quite curious.
Can I borrow it?
Sure. Last Sunday was the birthday of Jack's grandpa.
听短文，请根据所听内容。
从每小题所给的三个选项中选出一个最佳答案，并在答题卡上将对应选项
涂黑。
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目；
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
It was a sunny day, so the family decided to have the dinner party in the yard.
Before dinner, Jack's dad was busy putting balloons up on the trees.
Jack was making a special cake.
When dinner time came, Jack took out the cake.
It looked like a football.
Grandpa was very pleased to see the cake,
for he used to be a football player.
He was about to take a photo of the cake when a car stopped outside the yard.
Several old men got out.
Each of them was wearing a football uniform.
Grandpa was so excited to see them, because they were his friends in the college
football team. Grandpa said he would never forget this birthday party.
Last Sunday was the birthday of Jack's grandpa.
It was a sunny day, so the family decided to have the dinner party in the yard.
Before dinner, Jack's dad was busy putting balloons up on the trees.
Jack was making a special cake.
When dinner time came, Jack took out the cake.
It looked like a football.
Grandpa was very pleased to see the cake, for he used to be a football player.
He was about to take a photo of the cake when a car stopped outside the yard.
Several old men got out.
Each of them was wearing a football uniform.
Grandpa was so excited to see them, because they were his friends in the college
football team. Grandpa said he would never forget this birthday party.
D. Before Good morning, everyone.
听填信息。
你将听到关于学校音乐会筹备工作的会议内容，请根据所听内容填写下面
的信息卡，并将答案写在答题卡对应题目的答题位置上。
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
Today's meeting is about the preparations for next Thursday's concert, Sound of
Spring. You are the leaders of the preparation groups, and each group has its own
task. The job of Group 1 is to take care of the singers.
Make sure they get everything they need.
2 is supposed to make the music hall clean and tidy.
Please get it ready by Tuesday.
Group 3's duty is to carry the musical instruments on and off the stage.
Please be careful.
Group 4 is responsible for receiving the 20 honored guests on the list.
And you must get together at a school gate 30 minutes before the concert.
That's all about the tasks.
Now, do you have any questions?
Good morning, everyone.
Today's meeting is about the preparations for next Thursday's concert, Sound of
Spring. You are the leaders of the preparation groups, and each group has its own
task. The job of Group 1 is to take care of the singers.
Make sure they get everything they need.
Group 2 is supposed to make the music hall clean and tidy.
Please get it ready by Tuesday.
Group 3's duty is to carry the musical instruments on and off the
Please be careful.
Group 4 is responsible for receiving the 20 honored guests on the list.
And you must get together at a school gate 30 minutes before the concert.
That's all about the tasks.
Now, do you have any questions?
听力理解部分到此结束。
路。